<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>César Suárez, Software Engineer</title>
    <link>http://csuarez.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on César Suárez, Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 19:20:05 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://csuarez.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SuicideByStar</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/suicidebystar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 19:20:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/suicidebystar/</guid>
      <description>SuicideByStar is a webzine created in 2007 by a group of friends with the aim of promoting underground music. We talk about any kind of music we think could be interesting including metal, punk, electronic, rock and almost any kind of experimental music. Over the years we have created a forum that gathers a small, but strong, community which loves to talk about music and stupid things. Also, in 2015 we started an almost-monthly podcast where we speak about the latest releases of underground music and other related topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hate Love</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/hate-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 19:41:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/hate-love/</guid>
      <description>This browser extension blocks from your Twitter timeline the likes of users you follow.
Versions:
 Google Chrome Firefox Opera  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mana Calculator</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/mana-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 19:19:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/mana-calculator/</guid>
      <description>Mana Land Calculator is an Android app made with Ionic 1. This app allows you to calculate easily the number of lands you have to include in your Magic: The Gathering decks.
You can install it at Google Play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gridCake</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/gridcake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 19:19:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/gridcake/</guid>
      <description>gridCake is a gLite 3.2 compatible Java library. It has been developed using jLite and some of the gLite official libraries. The library is focused on hiding the complexities of the Grid, and it supports the core Grid services:
 Work management (WMS) Storage elements (gridFTP) Authentication (VMS) Credential delegation (MyProxy)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.E.E.T.</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/beet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 19:41:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/beet/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;&amp;gt; ABANDONED &amp;lt;&amp;lt;
B.E.E.T. (Bot Extremeño de Eventos Tecnológicos) is a project created to promote tech events in Extremadura. It gathers information about new events in beet.tech, to promote them automatically in Twitter at @beet_tech.
Why this? Extremadura is a big region but not very populated and it lacks of a hub (physical or digital) which joins the activity organized by a wide range of actors (university, local development groups, foundations, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other projects</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/other-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 19:20:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/other-projects/</guid>
      <description>Here I collect another small projects:
 Enhanced template for Hugo projects (+info). Symfony 2.0 Continous Integration boilerplate (+info). iBaazar: A little example of a CRUD application developed in Symfony2 (+info). javadoc2tex: An extended version of TexGen Doclet (+info). jlite CLI Plus: jLite CLI Plus on steroids! (+info).  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony &amp; Concurrencia</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/concurrency-desymfony/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/concurrency-desymfony/</guid>
      <description>You can check this talk in Youtube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Episodio VII: El Despertar de la Fuerza</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/php7-phpcaceres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/php7-phpcaceres/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB en la práctica: PyMongo &#43; Flask &#43; AngularJS</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/mongodb-juc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/mongodb-juc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 22:27:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALOE platform: an overview of a service-oriented architecture for research in breast cancer diagnosis supported by e-infrastructures</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/aloe-journal-image-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/aloe-journal-image-mining/</guid>
      <description>This article presents an overview of the ALOE platform. ALOE provides a service-oriented architecture aimed at the research in the early detection of breast cancer diagnosis. The development of the ALOE platform is carried out by collaboration among CETA-CIEMAT, INEGI, FMUP-HSJ and UA. ALOE supports two research lines in breast cancer diagnosis: the development of well performing computer aided diagnosis (CAD) systems and the development of new tools-based on e-learning techniques to improve radiologists training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance analysis of machine learning algorithms for automated diagnosis using a dataflow-based approach on the grid</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/performance-image-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/performance-image-mining/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning and imaging analytics are major algorithmic components of the software used by medical practitioners in the diagnosis and treatment of diseases. Whether employed by computer aided diagnosis (CADx) or content-based image retrieval (CBIR) tools, the accuracy and relevance of the results to the practitioner are paramount to the success of any such application. In order to improve on the existing results researchers often find themselves in the need to explore various approaches and methodologies, often using very large datasets and multiple sources of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El proyecto IMED: Investigando en métodos de diagnóstico asistido del cáncer de mama</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/imed-mama/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/imed-mama/</guid>
      <description>Accepted communication for the 2nd Spanish Congress of the Breast, Madrid October 22-24th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS en riguroso directo</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/angularjs-phpcaceres/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/angularjs-phpcaceres/</guid>
      <description>No slides for this talk, it was a live programming session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatización de tareas con Ansible</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/ansible-theevnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/ansible-theevnt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procesando datos con Hadoop: MapReduce y YARN</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/hadoop-juc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/hadoop-juc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dataflow-based approach to the design and distribution of medical image analytics</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/dataflow-ibergrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/dataflow-ibergrid/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning and imaging analytics are major algorithmic com-ponents of the software used by medical practitioners in the diagnosis and treatment of diseases. Whether employed by CADx (Computer Aided Diagnosis) or CBIR (Content Based Image Retrieval) tools, the accuracy and relevance of the results to the practitioner are paramount to the success of any such appli-cation. In order to improve on the existing results researchers often find themselves in the need to explore various approaches and methodologies, often using very large datasets and multiple sources of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALOE platform: An overview of a service-oriented architecture for research in breast cancer diagnosis supported by e-infrastructures</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/aloe-ibergrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/aloe-ibergrid/</guid>
      <description>This article presents an overview of the ALOE platform. ALOE provides a service-oriented architecture aimed at the research in the early detection of breast cancer diagnosis. The development of the ALOE platform is carried out by collaboration among CETA-CIEMAT, INEGI, FMUP-HSJ and UA. ALOE supports two research lines in breast cancer diagnosis: the development of well-performing Computer Aided Diagnosis (CAD) systems and the development of new tools based on e-Learning techniques to improve radiologists training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducción a SCRUM</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/scrum-ceta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/scrum-ceta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducción a GIT</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/git-ceta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/git-ceta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CAD Systems and E-Learning in radiologist training</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/cad-healthcom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/cad-healthcom/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CAD systems and e-Learning in radiologists training</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/cad-healthcom2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/cad-healthcom2013/</guid>
      <description>Breast cancer is one of the most diagnosed types of cancer. Early detection of breast cancer is the best practice to reduce its high mortality rate. Double reading is a common practice to avoid missed cancer cases during the lecture of mammograms. Due to the high cost of this technique and the lack of certified radiologists, computer-aided diagnosis systems have become very popular in the last decade. However, this technique is not perfect, and has some significant disadvantages, like higher recall rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CETA-CIEMAT: Salud &#43; Investigación</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/health-tic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/health-tic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the breast cancer diagnosis using digital repositories</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/breast-iwwbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/breast-iwwbio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the breast cancer diagnosis using digital repositories</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/breast-iwbbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/breast-iwbbio/</guid>
      <description>Breast cancer is one of the cancer type most diagnosed. Its causes are unknown so there is not an effective way to prevent it, which increases the mortality rate. The early detection of breast cancer is the best practice to reduce this rate. The double reading of mammograms is a common practice to reduce the rate of missed cancer, but it has a high cost. Computer Aided-diagnosis (CADx) Systems and Machine Learning Classifiers (MLCs) help to reduce this cost making automatic the second read of the mammograms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GridMed: Exploiting e-infrastructures for research in breast cancer CAD methods</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/gridmed-ceta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/gridmed-ceta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarabox: A platform to manage easily Grid storage</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/clarabox-gisela/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/clarabox-gisela/</guid>
      <description>The Grid [1] is a useful technology for sharing computational and storage resources between centers to speed up their research activities. It is a mature technology, widely used by the scientific community, but sometimes its use can be complex for final users. The main problem is that typical Grid front-ends are command line interfaces (CLI) which implies that final users have to memorize complex commands in order to start using the Grid services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a portlet for the GISELA Science Gateway to process hyperspectral images</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/portlet-gisela/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/portlet-gisela/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, Science Gateways are a trending topic in the Grid community. This kind of web portals allows sending jobs to a Grid infrastructure through a single process. Science Gateway users can configure the vast majority of the parameters Command Line Interface (CLI) may need. This way, it is possible to specify job input and output files, monitor the status of a job and download its output when finished.
Science Gateways are a good tool for accessing distributed resources, not only Grid resources, but also other paradigms, since Science Gateways are considered as an universal interface to many kinds of distributed computing resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IMED project: first results. Exploiting e-infrastructures for research in breast cancer CAD methods</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/imed-gisela/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/imed-gisela/</guid>
      <description>This paper describes the main results of the IMED Project. The IMED project is collaboration among CETA-CIEMAT in Spain, the Faculty of Engineering (FEUP) and the Faculty of Medicine of the University of Porto (FMUP) and Hospital Sao Joao in Porto (HSJ), Portugal, devoted to the research of computer-based detection and diagnosis methods of breast cancer.
The project activities can be separated in two main task groups: 1) data gathering and dataset building and 2) designing and modelling of Machine Learning Classifiers (MLC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gridCake &amp; gridCamp: Making the Grid easier</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/gridcake-egi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/gridcake-egi/</guid>
      <description>The Grid has shown to be a valuable technology for researchers. However, its frontends are usually designed for users with high computational skills and they aren&amp;rsquo;t very user-friendly. This fact typically causes contempt to final users, because they want to focus their efforts on their researches, skipping concepts not related with their studies. Also, the tools to make software that can interact with Grid services are complex, generally poorly documented and sometimes they don&amp;rsquo;t support latest Grid middleware versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integración Continua y Symfony2</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/ci-desymfony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/ci-desymfony/</guid>
      <description>You can check this talk in Youtube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gridCake &amp; gridCamp: Making the Grid easier</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/gridcake-egi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/gridcake-egi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BCDR: A breast cancer digital repository</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/bcdr-experimental-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/bcdr-experimental-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>Not available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIWAD: A software suite for building CAD methods</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/miwad-experimental-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/miwad-experimental-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>This paper introduces the “Mammography Image Workstation for Analysis and Diagnosis” (MIWAD), a novel software suite for processing, analysing and diagnosing mammography images. Main functionalities and components of MIWAD are also presented. Finally, this paper describes the use of MIWAD in the design and validation of breast cancer computer-aided diagnosis (CAD) methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony2: PHP no está muerto, estaba tomando cañas</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/symfony2-theevnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/symfony2-theevnt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Mammography-based Machine Learning Classifiers for Breast Cancer Diagnosis</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/discovering-journal-medical-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/discovering-journal-medical-systems/</guid>
      <description>This work explores the design of mammography-based machine learning classifiers (MLC) and proposes a new method to build MLC for breast cancer diagnosis. We massively evaluated MLC configurations to classify features vectors extracted from segmented regions (pathological lesion or normal tissue) on craniocaudal (CC) and/or mediolateral oblique (MLO) mammography image views, providing BI-RADS diagnosis. Previously, appropriate combinations of image processing and normalization techniques were applied to reduce image artifacts and increase mammograms details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony en la gestión de un centro de computación avanzada</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/talk/ceta-desymfony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/talk/ceta-desymfony/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CardioGrid: A framework for the analysis of cardiological signals in Grid computing</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/cardiogrid-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/cardiogrid-en/</guid>
      <description>The present paper describes the development of the CardioGrid framework into the Grid infrastructure. The core Grid services; workload management system (WMS), data management system and grid authentication have been implemented. Additionally, a Web-based tool -the CardioGrid portal-has been developed to facilitate the user interaction with the Grid. As a result, the user is able to process the electrocardiogram (ECG) signals obtained form a portable data acquisition device and to process them on the Grid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CardioGrid: Un Portal para el análisis de señales cardiológicas en Grid Computing</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/publication/cardiogrid-es/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/publication/cardiogrid-es/</guid>
      <description>El presente documento describe el desarrollo de CardioGrid en el marco de la infraestructura Grid. Los servicios Grid; Sistema de Gestión de Trabajos, Sistema de Gestión de Datos y la autenticación Grid se han puesto en práctica. Adi-cionalmente se desarrolló, una herramienta basada en un portal web para facilitar la interacción del usuario con la Grid. Como resultado, el usuario es capaz de procesar un electrocardiograma (ECG) obtenido a través de un dispositivo portátil de adquisición de datos en la Grid sin tener nin un conocimiento en dicha tecnología.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>