<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on César Suárez, Software Engineer</title>
    <link>http://csuarez.me/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on César Suárez, Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 19:20:05 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://csuarez.me/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SuicideByStar</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/suicidebystar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 19:20:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/suicidebystar/</guid>
      <description>SuicideByStar is a webzine created in 2007 by a group of friends with the aim of promoting underground music. We talk about any kind of music we think could be interesting including metal, punk, electronic, rock and almost any kind of experimental music. Over the years we have created a forum that gathers a small, but strong, community which loves to talk about music and stupid things. Also, in 2015 we started an almost-monthly podcast where we speak about the latest releases of underground music and other related topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hate Love</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/hate-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 19:41:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/hate-love/</guid>
      <description>This browser extension blocks from your Twitter timeline the likes of users you follow.
Versions:
 Google Chrome Firefox Opera  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mana Calculator</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/mana-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 19:19:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/mana-calculator/</guid>
      <description>Mana Land Calculator is an Android app made with Ionic 1. This app allows you to calculate easily the number of lands you have to include in your Magic: The Gathering decks.
You can install it at Google Play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gridCake</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/gridcake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 19:19:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/gridcake/</guid>
      <description>gridCake is a gLite 3.2 compatible Java library. It has been developed using jLite and some of the gLite official libraries. The library is focused on hiding the complexities of the Grid, and it supports the core Grid services:
 Work management (WMS) Storage elements (gridFTP) Authentication (VMS) Credential delegation (MyProxy)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B.E.E.T.</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/beet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 19:41:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/beet/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;&amp;gt; ABANDONED &amp;lt;&amp;lt;
B.E.E.T. (Bot Extremeño de Eventos Tecnológicos) is a project created to promote tech events in Extremadura. It gathers information about new events in beet.tech, to promote them automatically in Twitter at @beet_tech.
Why this? Extremadura is a big region but not very populated and it lacks of a hub (physical or digital) which joins the activity organized by a wide range of actors (university, local development groups, foundations, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other projects</title>
      <link>http://csuarez.me/project/other-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 19:20:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csuarez.me/project/other-projects/</guid>
      <description>Here I collect another small projects:
 Enhanced template for Hugo projects (+info). Symfony 2.0 Continous Integration boilerplate (+info). iBaazar: A little example of a CRUD application developed in Symfony2 (+info). javadoc2tex: An extended version of TexGen Doclet (+info). jlite CLI Plus: jLite CLI Plus on steroids! (+info).  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>