<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on César Suárez, Software Engineer</title>
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on César Suárez, Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ALOE platform: an overview of a service-oriented architecture for research in breast cancer diagnosis supported by e-infrastructures</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/aloe-journal-image-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/aloe-journal-image-mining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article presents an overview of the ALOE platform. ALOE provides a service-oriented architecture aimed at the research in the early detection of breast cancer diagnosis. The development of the ALOE platform is carried out by collaboration among CETA-CIEMAT, INEGI, FMUP-HSJ and UA. ALOE supports two research lines in breast cancer diagnosis: the development of well performing computer aided diagnosis (CAD) systems and the development of new tools-based on e-learning techniques to improve radiologists training. All ALOE modules are designed to work as a whole system but can be used individually in other systems and expose RESTful interfaces to be exploited by third party systems. ALOE components make use of e-Infrastructure resources to accomplish their tasks. The final objective of this work is to provide a reference platform for researchers, specialists, and students in breast cancer diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance analysis of machine learning algorithms for automated diagnosis using a dataflow-based approach on the grid</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/performance-image-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/performance-image-mining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning and imaging analytics are major algorithmic components of the software used by medical practitioners in the diagnosis and treatment of diseases. Whether employed by computer aided diagnosis (CADx) or content-based image retrieval (CBIR) tools, the accuracy and relevance of the results to the practitioner are paramount to the success of any such application. In order to improve on the existing results researchers often find themselves in the need to explore various approaches and methodologies, often using very large datasets and multiple sources of information. Each of these trials can, by itself, be a very time-consuming operation. One tried and true strategy to speed up operations is the use of a distributed computing platform (delivering the computational load to a number of machines). This raises a set of problems which are often orthogonal to a researcher&amp;rsquo;s interest such as which algorithmic implementations scale or how to distribute data and tasks on the grid. In this article, we present a framework that empowers researchers to quickly design sets of tests, schedule their execution and have them automatically allocated to a grid environment for execution. We describe the design and implementation of the solution, and present as an example an experiment concerning the classification of mammography segmentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El proyecto IMED: Investigando en métodos de diagnóstico asistido del cáncer de mama</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/imed-mama/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/imed-mama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Accepted communication for the 2nd Spanish Congress of the Breast, Madrid October 22-24th.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A dataflow-based approach to the design and distribution of medical image analytics</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/dataflow-ibergrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/dataflow-ibergrid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning and imaging analytics are major algorithmic com-ponents of the software used by medical practitioners in the diagnosis and treatment of diseases. Whether employed by CADx (Computer Aided Diagnosis) or CBIR (Content Based Image Retrieval) tools, the accuracy and relevance of the results to the practitioner are paramount to the success of any such appli-cation. In order to improve on the existing results researchers often find themselves in the need to explore various approaches and methodologies, often using very large datasets and multiple sources of information. Each of these trials can, by itself, be a very time-consuming operation. One tried and true strategy to speed up operations is the use of a distributed computing platform (delivering the computational load to a number of machines). This raises a set of problems which are often orthogonal to a researcher&amp;rsquo;s interest such as which algorithmic implementations scale or how to distribute data and tasks on the grid. In this article we present a framework that empowers researchers to quickly design sets of tests, schedule their execution and have them automatically dis-tributed on a grid environment. We describe the design and implementation of the solution, and present as an example an experiment concerning the classification of mammography segmentations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALOE platform: An overview of a service-oriented architecture for research in breast cancer diagnosis supported by e-infrastructures</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/aloe-ibergrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/aloe-ibergrid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article presents an overview of the ALOE platform. ALOE provides a service-oriented architecture aimed at the research in the early detection of breast cancer diagnosis. The development of the ALOE platform is carried out by collaboration among CETA-CIEMAT, INEGI, FMUP-HSJ and UA. ALOE supports two research lines in breast cancer diagnosis: the development of well-performing Computer Aided Diagnosis (CAD) systems and the development of new tools based on e-Learning techniques to improve radiologists training. All ALOE modules are designed to work as a whole system but can be used individually in other systems and expose RESTful interfaces to be exploited by third party systems. ALOE components make use of e-Infrastructure resources to accomplish their tasks. The final objective of this work is to provide a reference platform for researchers, specialists, and students in breast cancer diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CAD systems and e-Learning in radiologists training</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/cad-healthcom2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/cad-healthcom2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Breast cancer is one of the most diagnosed types of cancer. Early detection of breast cancer is the best practice to reduce its high mortality rate. Double reading is a common practice to avoid missed cancer cases during the lecture of mammograms. Due to the high cost of this technique and the lack of certified radiologists, computer-aided diagnosis systems have become very popular in the last decade. However, this technique is not perfect, and has some significant disadvantages, like higher recall rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, e-Learning (the use of information and communication technologies for learning or ICTs) during medical education has been demonstrated to be a useful resource in the training of new physicians. In radiology is typical to use anonymized cases to train new radiologists. This practice perfectly fits with some e-Learning practices, based on the use of simulated or real cases combined with auto-evaluation tools. The advantages and disadvantages of CAD systems as a basis to develop self-assessment e-Learning tools are discussed in this work. Some CAD system problems like high recall rates are less important in education than in the clinical practice, but the higher rate of false-positives could be a problem, especially in the use of CAD systems by inexperienced radiologists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these topics in mind, the IMED project (collaboration among CETA-CIEMAT, INEGI and FMUP-HSJ created to find new ways to improve breast cancer diagnosis) is enhancing e-Learning tools with CAD systems. This development is based on three tools developed by the project: (1) BCDR, a repository which stores clinical data and mammograms related to breast cancer studies, (2) MIWAD, a workstation with CAD features that helps doctors during the breast cancer diagnosis and (3) a set of Machine Learning Classifiers (MLCs) integrated in MIWAD and trained with BCDR data, with the ability to classify abnormalities in mammograms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new training tool is called Aloe, and it is in its early stages of development. It is divided in a REST service and in a web frontend which will implement a workflow that will allow students to auto-evaluate their skills reading mammograms. An alpha version will be released soon to obtain early feedback from users, in order to check the usefulness of CAD systems in e-Learning methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the breast cancer diagnosis using digital repositories</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/breast-iwbbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/breast-iwbbio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Breast cancer is one of the cancer type most diagnosed. Its causes are unknown so there is not an effective way to prevent it, which increases the mortality rate. The early detection of breast cancer is the best practice to reduce this rate. The double reading of mammograms is a common practice to reduce the rate of missed cancer, but it has a high cost. Computer Aided-diagnosis (CADx) Systems and Machine Learning Classifiers (MLCs) help to reduce this cost making automatic the second read of the mammograms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collaboration between CETA-CIEMAT, INEGI and FMUP-HSJ has generated a set of valuable resources to improve the breast cancer diagnosis process. We aim to achieve a reference repository for breast cancer diagnosis with BCDR, improving the existing implementations by storing a large number of annotated diagnosed cases reviewed by specialists, so researchers can have a reliable source of information for their researches. Using the BCDR data, the main MLCs algorithms are being tested in order to find the best configuration for obtaining accurate automatic diagnosis tool. MIWAD is a workstation that eases the specialist’s job in their diagnoses. It is a rich client for BCDR, and offers a set of tools that ease the breast screening and the integration of any MLCs to its workflow. All these resources have been built on top of DRI, a software platform aimed to ease the creation and management of digital repositories over heterogeneous storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work describes the advances made and the future work of the IMED project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarabox: A platform to manage easily Grid storage</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/clarabox-gisela/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/clarabox-gisela/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Grid [1] is a useful technology for sharing computational and storage resources between centers to speed up their research activities. It is a mature technology, widely used by the scientific community, but sometimes its use can be complex for final users. The main problem is that typical Grid front-ends are command line interfaces (CLI) which implies that final users have to memorize complex commands in order to start using the Grid services. This is a big limitation, because a small number of researchers have the skills needed to use a CLI without a specific training. This fact has caused rejection of Grid technology for many users. Nowadays the Grid community is making a lot of efforts to develop Science Gateways and Grid portals to make easier the use of Grid environments. Almost all of these developments are focused in the computational capabilities of the Grid, making easier the process of sending and monitoring jobs, the creation of job workflows, or the retrieval of job outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These projects usually ignore the storage capabilities of the Grid, which present the same problems that the computational capabilities: the complexity of its use.
Clarabox is a platform designed for allowing easy management of files stored in a Grid environment using the LCG File Catalog (LFC). The architecture of Clarabox is divided in three main components: (1) a LFC PHP library which has been developed from scratch, (2) a REST-compliant web service which exposes the methods of the PHP library, and (3) a web front-end which uses the web service to provide a user-friendly interface for managing easily the data stored on a Grid infrastructure even for users without previous Grid technology knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design of the web front-end has been inspired by the most used file browsers (like Windows Explorer or Nautilus), so its use will be familiar for anyone with a basic experience with computers. Clarabox makes possible to download and upload files, to browse in the LFC file structure, to make replicas of the files and all the expected functions implemented in a normal file browser. Also Clarabox will manage the security in a transparent way, so the user does not need to have previous knowledge about Grid certificates in order to start storing their data in a Grid storage service. This work describes the architecture of Clarabox, technical details of the development process of all of its components, how difficulties appeared under the development were managed and the future of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a portlet for the GISELA Science Gateway to process hyperspectral images</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/portlet-gisela/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/portlet-gisela/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, Science Gateways are a trending topic in the Grid community. This kind of web portals allows sending jobs to a Grid infrastructure through a single process. Science Gateway users can configure the vast majority of the parameters Command Line Interface (CLI) may need. This way, it is possible to specify job input and output files, monitor the status of a job and download its output when finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science Gateways are a good tool for accessing distributed resources, not only Grid resources, but also other paradigms, since Science Gateways are considered as an universal interface to many kinds of distributed computing resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the GISELA Science Gateway development environment has been used to build a portlet for running a hyperspectral image processing application. Hyperspectral imaging, like other spectral imaging models, collect and process information gathered across the electromagnetic spectrum. The human eye sees visible light in three bands (red, green, and blue), however spectral imaging divides the spectrum into more bands. This technique of separating band images can be extended beyond the visible ones. The ported algorithm is known as Pixel Purity Index (PPI) and it is used for finding those pixels that present the most spectrally purity (extreme) value in multispectral and hyperspectral images. The Pixel Purity Index is computed by repeatedly projecting n-dimensional scatterplots onto a random unit vector. The extreme pixels in each projection are those pixels that fall onto the ends of the unit vector. The total number of times each pixel is marked as extreme is noted. A result image is created in which the value of each pixel corresponds to the number of times that the pixel was recorded as extreme. This algorithm is very useful for identifying which pixels are pure. Purity means that a pixel is only composed of a unique substance such as water, forest, ground, etc. The porting of the PPI algorithm to the GISELA Science Gateway will allow users to process 186 a wide range of hyperspectral images in a reasonable cost time. A single execution on a workstation is a high time-consuming task owing to the size of the images (can be sizes measured on several Gigabytes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work deals with the experience obtained during the application porting. It has been made through the GISELA Science Gateway development environment. The work also shows the way initial problems were solved and the procedure for performing an application successfully porting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IMED project: first results. Exploiting e-infrastructures for research in breast cancer CAD methods</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/imed-gisela/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/imed-gisela/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper describes the main results of the IMED Project. The IMED project is collaboration among CETA-CIEMAT in Spain, the Faculty of Engineering (FEUP) and the Faculty of Medicine of the University of Porto (FMUP) and Hospital Sao Joao in Porto (HSJ), Portugal, devoted to the research of computer-based detection and diagnosis methods of breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project activities can be separated in two main task groups: 1) data gathering and dataset building and 2) designing and modelling of Machine Learning Classifiers (MLC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first stage, a set of real patient cases (clinical data and mammography images) provided by the Faculty of Medicine has been digitalised. These cases are properly anonymised to be compliant to the privacy regulations. Besides, a digital repository, called Breast Cancer Digital Repository (BCDR), has been designed and implemented to store all the data from the digitalised set of cases from the FMUP. The metadata of the digital repository is a subset of the DICOM-SR standard customised according the requirements of the staff of the FMUP and Hospital Sao Joao. The BCDR is being hosted in an instance of the Digital Repository Infrastructure (DRI), a software platform aimed at simplifying and reducing the cost of hosting digital repositories over Grid infrastructures and that has been developed at CETA-CIEMAT. Currently, the BCDR contains cases of 1610 patients with mammography and ultrasound images, clinical history, lesion segmentations and selected 18 pre-computed image-based descriptors. Patient cases are BI-RADS classified and annotated by specialised radiologists. At the time of writing, the BCDR includes 820 segmented lesions (276 biopsy-proven).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this first stage, a software suite called Mammography Image Workstation for Analysis and Diagnosis (MIWAD) has been also developed. MIWAD consists of a desktop application, called MIWAD-DB, that allows storage, retrieval and management of patient and case information of the BCDR and a specialised graphical user interface, called MIWAD-CAD, for processing, analysing and diagnosing mammography images by combining digital image processing, pattern recognition and artificial intelligence techniques. MIWAD is currently being used to feed the BCDR with new patient cases from the FMUP and it is also used by experts from the FMUP and Hospital Sao Joao to evaluate and classify those cases. As previously mentioned, the project has a second stage that consists of the design and implementation of automatic classifiers for breast cancer detection and diagnosis. The content of the BCDR is used to build datasets to train machine learning classifiers to be later integrated in MIWAD for automatic classification to be used by specialists as second opinion to support their diagnosis and patient management decisions. Grid computing is been used to make massive explorations of artificial neural networks (ANN) and support vector machines (SVM) classifiers to find well performing classifiers for our datasets. At the time of writing, results between 0,661 and 0,996 ROC Az has been obtained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a future work, the project plans to open the content of the BCDR to the public. It is also planned to feed the repository with new cases provided by the FMUP that will contain high resolution mammography images from a digital mammography station. Besides, The BCDR data model will be evolved to be full-compliant with the DICOM-SR standard for breast imaging. According the design and development of classifiers, the project will continue to evaluate which image descriptors are more suitable for breast imaging and new MLCs configuration will be evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a conclusion, the IMED project should be considered as a good case of exploitation of e- infrastructures for collaborative research as both GRID storage and computing capacities are being used for storing the BCDR content and evaluating classifiers configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gridCake &amp; gridCamp: Making the Grid easier</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/gridcake-egi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/gridcake-egi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Grid has shown to be a valuable technology for researchers. However, its frontends are usually designed for users with high computational skills and they aren&amp;rsquo;t very user-friendly. This fact typically causes contempt to final users, because they want to focus their efforts on their researches, skipping concepts not related with their studies. Also, the tools to make software that can interact with Grid services are complex, generally poorly documented and sometimes they don&amp;rsquo;t support latest Grid middleware versions. This makes very difficult to develop new user interfaces for Grid services friendlier than the existing ones. This work will deal about the problems with existing Grid user inter- faces and development tools, and it will describe the development of a very easy to use Java Grid library called gridCake, and a Grid web portal called gridCamp built with gridCake, which mixes Grid functionalities with social network features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BCDR: A breast cancer digital repository</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/bcdr-experimental-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/bcdr-experimental-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIWAD: A software suite for building CAD methods</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/miwad-experimental-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/miwad-experimental-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper introduces the “Mammography Image Workstation for Analysis and Diagnosis” (MIWAD), a novel software suite for processing, analysing and diagnosing mammography images. Main functionalities and components of MIWAD are also presented. Finally, this paper describes the use of MIWAD in the design and validation of breast cancer computer-aided diagnosis (CAD) methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Mammography-based Machine Learning Classifiers for Breast Cancer Diagnosis</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/discovering-journal-medical-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/discovering-journal-medical-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work explores the design of mammography-based machine learning classifiers (MLC) and proposes a new method to build MLC for breast cancer diagnosis. We massively evaluated MLC configurations to classify features vectors extracted from segmented regions (pathological lesion or normal tissue) on craniocaudal (CC) and/or mediolateral oblique (MLO) mammography image views, providing BI-RADS diagnosis. Previously, appropriate combinations of image processing and normalization techniques were applied to reduce image artifacts and increase mammograms details. The method can be used under different data acquisition circumstances and exploits computer clusters to select well performing MLC configurations. We evaluated 286 cases extracted from the repository owned by HSJ-FMUP, where specialized radiologists segmented regions on CC and/or MLO images (biopsies provided the golden standard). Around 20,000 MLC configurations were evaluated, obtaining classifiers achieving an area under the ROC curve of 0.996 when combining features vectors extracted from CC and MLO views of the same case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CardioGrid: A framework for the analysis of cardiological signals in Grid computing</title>
      <link>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/cardiogrid-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://0.0.0.0:6789/publication/cardiogrid-en/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present paper describes the development of the CardioGrid framework into the Grid infrastructure. The core Grid services; workload management system (WMS), data management system and grid authentication have been implemented. Additionally, a Web-based tool -the CardioGrid portal-has been developed to facilitate the user interaction with the Grid. As a result, the user is able to process the electrocardiogram (ECG) signals obtained form a portable data acquisition device and to process them on the Grid. Once the CardioGrid portal is prompted and the user identity is verified through a digital X.509 certificate, the operator may either upload new raw ECG data to the grid storage elements or use already stored data. Then, subsequent analytics from these data are performed as Grid jobs and relevant medical quantities are derived through a middleware job retrieval mechanism. In summary, this paper describes the development of a medical Grid based system, and its integration to an existing platform for digital repositories infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>